...project astoria building great windows apps from your android code.
I'm john justice the director program management project astoria with me is rajesh some
...director of engineering project astoria today we're going to talk about what project
...it is and show you how you can take advantage of it to bring your applications to windows mobile
now I just found out that this is starting the exact same time as the nfl
draft so if any of you follow american football I'm impressed
with your dedication but you're here...exciting happens please feel free shout.
All right before you started at the end of this will have this q
r code up this is the link to our session evaluation...put it up at the end but
if you have comments for us please do send them along especially if you
like to talk we do take that's a pretty seriously.
As you saw in the key notes windows ten represents a significant opportunity for
use developers it's going to help you building engaging
and diverse experiences scaling from mobile the
...you'll be able to reach over a billion users.
A variety of devices around the world through universal windows apps.
While universal windows apps will have the best reach and
the deepest integration with windows many of you have code
and other places that you'd like to move to windows.
Of course if you already have universal
...you are in the best position possible to take advantage of
...windows platform.
If you have win thirty-two or dot net apps we welcome them...also head of the game if you have
code from the web you-can directly target project spartan.
Ortiz apache cordova or...hosted web apps.
To seamlessly stay up-to-date with your website
...native access to the universal windows platform if you have apps based on middleware like
...or unity welcome those two and finally.
If you have apps from other mobile platforms including both ios an android we
welcome them as well windows provides bridges for
...is developers to bring your code from all these platforms to windows.
Just a minute we're going to dive into building a windows a story app.
But, first let's take
a minute talk about project astoria and project island would side-by-side.
First both projects are free st...that will be available later this year.
Project island...that nate
...user objective c code from your ios applications
development in visual studio good code reuse.
And, you get full integration with the universal windows platform a story brings both java
...android code the windows platform with.
...user existing id we support equips intelligence
...android studio.
With the story...many apps
...zero or very little modification art
...project historian.
...over to the...dame charred will show...preview of a project
...demo app called timber now we're going to...bit deeper.
So, timber with...be is a sample...the going to put up on get hub is
opensource you can check it out yourself in app that
...hope you find the national park that's rate for you all right so let's start on an android phone
since ...originally built for built for android.
I can like parks or passed by swiping left to right.
They don't like that one...trees.
Are down with
...nice and snowing okay we'll take a look at where this park is by clicking on the location
icon noone rajesh clicked on that called into the google location service of
course by...windows I would expect us to use the windows location service?
Okay, now I do like a...click into
a little bit now I want to share this with some folks.
So, we click on share here this is the android share intent that pulls up the android share
...if I...windows of course...windows share contracts.
Okay, the app also uses google maps to locate the
...in the windows apps of course I would want being maps.
If I wanted to add a comment on the
part timber would use the android keyboard of course on windows and...the excellent
windows keyboard with its excellent windows emerging l switch over to windows phone.
...this is timber.
Repackage as a windows app the app uses a hundred-percent of the
...code that you just are running on...android phone.
But, we're just reusing the code.
...delivering the user experience performance and security
that windows users expect use of told us time and...they love the windows phone design
and expect apps to fit into the windows phone experience.
...windows...like the part that I like.
All right let's see of our without one is...
Allocation just works calling into the windows location service let's go over to share.
Now when we share this is
...up the window share menu without any code change.
Ok.
Now let's go over the maps you can see these maps these are being
maps that are being added in again there was we'll show you...exactly how to make this change.
Now let's add a comment.
...just like I hope the windows keyboard came up was the
...keyboard the world I think right now ok now I want to do something that the android app
isn't able to do we're going to go in and this app uses lifestylesso,
we wrote a few lines of code to do this will show you how in a minute let's go in and take
...can see the timbers alive tile now to get apps like timber.
Users
will get them from the windows store just like any other windows app will show you...just a minute.
Our but first let's go and build and app.
You another developers of tolls over the...to reuse your code
user familiar id and keep your existing workflow in tools.
So, in this demo
...going to show you how to how to create a windows app using your android code.
Reuse it or using your familiar id
...current developing machine will do some live debugging will integrate with windows services
and will integrate with windows features all of very little effort now we're...going to take us through this?
Nobody first step.
...very first step is to find or more changes...I have to make the app
also I'm at the project...app analysis page which is part of the
windows development center I'm going to click on this link and upload the
ap k of the original android app.
This web page perform this static analysis of the...
It identifies all the google place services that are used by the app we
also take a stab at converting all the android icons into windows tight
assets and you developers have a choice of using the icons converted by the web
page or replacing them with your own assets these are the icons that are service converted.
I'm now going to drill in on google place services.
To see what the app what the web page
...web page correctly identified that this app is using three google
place services google location google maps and google klout messaging.
We're not going to show you how to convert this app into a windows
...with no core change.
To make that possible reorder service interop library this
service interop library automatically converts all the google calls to microsoft
equivalents in this in this example google location services converted
...windows location service google maps as
converter bing maps and google klout notifications removed google
...messaging is mapped to windows notifications.
The next step is to...click on this lincoln download the
st gave the project astoria sdk this is a one-time operation
but to save some time you've already done this on this demo machine.
I'm now going to switch to intelligent.
The project
...sdk comes with the tool that automatically...file.
To allow you to build flavors for both windows
an android so-you developers do not have to for code.
It also...it also automatically ads and dependency
microsoft services sorry windows version of your app can use the microsoft services and
sort-of google services this...purely optional...welcome to do the step I hand.
I'm now going to compile the app.
While the app is compiling I'm going to use a tool called w connect this
tool also as part of the sdk and the tool w connect takes
an ip address and connects to be windows emulator...running on this machine.
In this demo we're going to show you the emulator but we also support debugging and
applying to real devices both where usb and wi-fi.
We support that so this tool connectsthe windows
...android debug bridge also known as eighty.
We support all the
...commands that...be familiar with...to give you three examples.
Ab devices which lists all the
connector devices as you can see the emulator showed up as a valid device.
Ab...alice which
...the directly listing on the emulator and finally
Which allows you to see the logs generated...application?
More switch back to intelligent and
...I'll shows up as a valid deployment target so I'm going to
click all can deploy the app to the emulator while
this is happening I want explain what is happening under the colors we take the
ack and package convert that into a windows app x
this allows us to run the app as a native windows app in clustered and secure environment.
The app asks me for my location and I'm going to click yes.
I click on the location icon and this location information is
now provided by microsoft location windows location service.
Going to click on the in click on this park.
And, you know, this map comes from being map
... I'm not going to show you everything here but what we saw the consumer demo we just work.
...navigate back to the main page so,
you live debugging so I'm going to like this spark.
Right...a big point in the trigger right function and we support
your identical debugging workflow you can separate points you can step into
cody can step over code you can watch variables really the whole thing.
Now that I have shown you how to convert your.
Android...into a basic windows app with...core change
it's time to add of...lines of code to take advantage of some of the features that
are uniquely available only on windows so we're going to show you two things
...add some...for lifestyles and,
then it will show you how to map from google klout messaging to windows notifications.
So, I'm going to switch to the windows tile updated or java file.
And, the first thing I'm going to do is add a bunch of imports.
And, then I'm going to scroll down to the update tile function
...just a few lines of code for lifestyles.
...scroll so you can see what I've...just a few lines of code.
This is the exact same windows live tile api what we have done is
we've made that api accessible to you in java projections.
Now I'm going to...and deploy the app.
To the emulator so why this is happening I wanted...speak a little bit about what happens
in the real-world the real-world your app so...send...notification to a
cloud messaging service which will then redirect that onto the device.
In this demo all we're going to simulate that using fiddler
...have also made...really easy for you to changer apps...because
you're, you're you have apps...has to take care of what android apps and windows apps so,
it's...a one-line url change on the app so
...code to router message to a windows device.
Based on a windows prefix.
So, this app is not deployed on the phone on the emulator.
So, I'm actually going to win the app back to start so that you can see the lifetime.
And, I'm going to copy the registration id from lock-out here.
As you can see the starts with the keyword microsoft this is the...the app so that this is
this registration id comes from microsoft device and for them to use the
right url descended back to the microsoft device.
So, I'm going to copy this url.
I want to based this in fiddler.
Now using...ascending and http...of the same attribute request that your apps awards
...the cloud.
I'm going to bring the app...the very first thing that I'm going to do ascended...notification.
And, ...got
that those and this happened without any code change because we automatically mapped google
klout messaging of windows notifications I'm not going to make a one-word change the send
...a...tile update.
I...tools to...tile and if you a pay attention to the tyler want to see that flip.
Multiplied once more it flip but...back very quickly.
Well, the...supposed to flip the school system
and development so as we used for this is actually a live demo using real
connectivity before the demo we tried this ten out of ten times and it worked every single time.
So, now that...built I've shown you how to build a windows
app using your android code...you to...ingestion process.
Eleven out of level.
the windows this is the same develop windows dep center that...use for audio windows apps regardless of
where it came from so you use this speech to manage of in thirty-two apps project island
what apps and everything else I'm going to click on this link and upload
...that we just built...save you some time...to show you how the pages going to look after the upload
...finished...you can see that a bunch of...your.
And, now the now you're ready to hit submit as soon as you
hit submit your the app is now going to be available on the windows
...after the ingestion still ingestion process concludes.
So, that's sort of concludes the store ingestion process.
We know that many of you use amac as your primary development machine and you've thought about
you as...the entire workflow that I showed you here is also runs on
...so I'm just going to switch to a amac machine and, show you that.
So, that's analogy and this is the windows emulator running on a...so,
that...develop experience demo...okay all right.
And,...the networking...were playing with...for a little while but...came through
the end okay well we just saw we took some android code
we reuse it to build a great windows app...windows...including keyboard and
window sharing contract which are how to debugged we showed how to...with a...tile.
Also demonstrated just how easy it is to use the
project story interop library to redirect your...your google service
calls to microsoft services...just a simple configuration change and no code.
And, finally we showed you using the windows developer portal both
...analyzer app and that german recommended changes and then manage...boarding of europe.
...how do this actually work.
As you can imagine there's some pretty significant differences and architecture and design between windows and
...platforms so to say...is developers a ton of time.
We've done a lot of work translating
these concepts and rewrite translate these concepts.
Doing the heavy lifting for you re mapping the key
user experiences cloud services and platform api is...into each of these.
...start with user experience when someone uses a
project story app they...experience to be the same as any other windows app so windows
ensures that touch input interaction window
in notification another aspects experience all work well windows apps
...with product story will be available for download from the windows store along with any other
windows apps users don't generally pay a lot of attention to what tech...
powers and app as long as the app delivers great experience performance quality and security.
So, this is how timber would show up in the store if I were...meant that if we pulled of its
project pageit's going to download like any other
...once...downloaded...available for media use we ought to do anything special here.
Okay,
so, we're window...all of the most important experiences for apps built from project
...project historian we recreated controls
interactions and experiences to match the windows you...and to eliminate any clashes
...interface concepts so even though I'm just showing one example this
mapping of experiences in concepts is the same thing we do all over the system
...I concepts api mappings or kernel level...calls.
So, here's one example we're going into copy and paste
...windows customers expect copy and paste to work like
it does ever world some windows.
So, this is our app...project story works.
When you select text?
It looks like just like expect that's different from how
...on android on android it looks like this.
...the copy button is directly above on
...floats the top of as a menu looks pretty
different in a little bit jarring we didn't want those things so we replace them for you automatically.
Now if I go to paste the paces well on windows I use the keyboard that
using the pace but...always available...the keyboard on android I have a separate
pace button it looks pretty difference we removed all these jarring differences.
...right next up let's talk about services windows apps built
with project astoria they need to light...engaging user...generating revenue for
you is developers use a number of cloud services to do this
...providing a rich sdk for microsoft services in java to meet your needs so you can
create revenue ad opportunities with microsoft ads and analytics use
support framingham another popular models within app...
Powerful services like xbox live windows notification bing maps
locationsall these enable you to create engaging experiences.
The platform side when you're at uses low-level or
core platform capabilities including graphics files sensors
etc windows takes care of mapping those out too now some of this technically
...about mapping api is just one call to another but fundamental platform concepts like
lifecycle when apps...suspended when they're killed etc what apps
...processes are allowed to run a background or resource
...attribution and management so the windows knows exactly
what's executing using system resources if you're app uses sensors
other local hardware local files or other resources like contacts.
Project story redirect you to the...windows experience.
Good performance and long battery life are critical to a
good user experience we get both of these from...pieces of tech.
First we run these apps in the universal windows platform container applying the
same resource management policies that we apply everywhere else is important for performance
and battery life but also for security which...talk about next the second key
piece...mapping itself what's important about this is how we do it
our subsystem does not run a second os we're not running a second
...instead we've done the harder work of redirecting each of the low-level
calls you need directly to the windows kernel
this low-level mapping significantly improves efficiency through close integration with the rest of windows.
Now switch to how the universal platform sandbox another investments are making make sure your
users will be confident that all apps that come from the windows store regardless of the code base
they're built on are safe source security model is designed to protect the user
in multiple ways against multiple points of threat.
on the platform side we build the system and the architecture security in mind reducing the chance of
mahler taking advantage vulnerabilities and system so what does this look like well first we start with the
universal windows platform sandbox we build this on top of any base security we get
the android subsystem running in the universal windows platform sandbox results and
tighter control over app behavior and system resource access this cuts down in the
...surface area reducing prop possible threats compared to android, for example,
several common mal were attacks on android use...as a means to...the user or
the device on windows we tightly control the sm interface only trusted apps can run.
Next up is security through the store.
We have a sophisticated store ingestion process that screens developers and apps to ensure that good
apps from good developers with a good history are available in the windows store.
Now I'm sure that everyone in this room
...great apps that are highly trustworthy but for the people outside the room right
things that may not be we...make sure that we have good screening finally monitoring
rapid response with user's permission are monitoring services look at the anonymous
...telemetry and we look for how we can...malicious behavior for maps users
have direct channel microsoft report malicious or suspicious behavior and any apps and we have a team
of security research researchers...monitoring are devices and the android
ecosystem to identify the latest threats and vulnerabilities will provide rapid updates to the system
...and through the store will act quickly and user reports address potential threats.
All right what's recap so we just saw
have windows ten provides a bridge to bring your android code
windows we releasing this sdk for free later this year.
...welcoming your android code.
We support your id...on your deb machine.
We support integration into windows including live tiles and all this ends up in the windows
store.
Now thanks for coming today if you'd like to learn more I encourage you to stop
...booth tester the sdk...in a hands-on,
hands-on a quick start challenge.
If you like to help
...shape the technology or just follow along sign up for updates on our website.
Linkedin channel nine videos blog posts and samples over the coming days.
...if you have any questions we save a good amount of time for qa here at the end and then movie at
the windows insiders lounge for the next chunk of time to answering more.
All right so if you have questions please come up the microphones and ask and we'll try
...the you got.
Rajesh...come back up the degree.
So, the few questions my first as we use a
lot of low-level socket programming api in our cplus-plus
code for you support like multicast and broadcast and all that stuff.
...about the general way that we go through supporting
all stuff we do is we start working folks
...the folks in our tap programmer or more now we're talking about this we go
into static analysis over all the app so that compatibility wizard is based on we have
engine that can go and find out what are all the calls that you make local calls all the remote calls all
those things and then we go look across all of those api eyes we say okay which ones
we cluster analysis say what which are the ones that cluster together with the most valuable we prioritize
...that way so I can tell you that...have the most useful
calls in that area I can't tell you we have one particular one or another but if you send-me...I can ...you know,
for the particular thing or if you want to make sure we have coverage for stop
...both will scan your apple make sure we have the right stuff cool okay and then to really other quick
question that infers like background services you just kind of ignore those
unassuming because you can't no actually we're building support for background services in the
code that were demo ing today we don't have it to show it doesn't work yet but we're working on
building and right now there's there's some there's some real differences in a way that
we handle background services and with android handles background services but we've got a mapping
...we can do school and it's way much on intention to
the user and control so we want to provide a trustworthy like battery efficient background
implementation that's the trick their background services on android it's pretty much open
...season so you can do anything with the background services and just
draining battery nothing we're trying to make sure that doesn't happen and then lastly did volume keys
work can I get those...is that still kind of model and.
Volume keys ...mean a and
...hardware volume...can I get the key events rhythms.
The key that's for this to encrypt the android subsystem no, I mean volume keys like to can
...if the user uses the volume keys and uone overvalued
...sorry...you're asking a licensing conan techno hardware support
...yet but yes you should be also for volume keys we-re map those is like
back button all the rest that kind of stuff so was we'll go inject those arabia's thank you
sure that let's...over the next one over here...altering back and forth
...around the feeding and like the system controls...
One is how much you...transfer...is like how much more can we do to try
...make it fit within the windows os and...what are the
...requirements around here if we don't even yes ok so,
let's start with you saw some stuff we showed here already we showed re mapping some of the
...system dialogues we-re mapped into all of a system called
...we're taking care of those one after another to make sure
those are all feel like windows we can't go in and change the app itself the way
the app looks internally was not calling intomaking system calls so,
that's really up to the developer we don't currently have any policies that require
you make significant changes there were ...be set noses we as we get a little
closer further on I can tell you that we're trying wherever we can to make it just
feel natural now there's a bunch of stuff that to be clear if you want to take advantage of things
like adaptive ey that will help you scale your app across different screen sizes and
things like that just doesn't exist on android that something you can only get by going and doing
something universal from the start so you want to go target hollow lens and xbox
and desktop a mobile and all those things you have to go there you could try to
code all that stuff manually but I...better patches...start the uwuniversal windows up?
...there...what if I already have a samurai
...android application that we want to use here because the development team
...each are they did it shared code with ios and there's no management
effort to target windows view so...users...nike case
...I would use...takers...target windows directly etc what the problem is
...management has no interest in creating the few level components for that so we have the views done
...android using the android widgets...android services and get the ip k out
...just drop this into windows phone how do you I haven't tried I don't know
that works work-site, you know, the evaluation we
...out that's a I would expect most...
...do examine development just...just a target windows...it's pretty straightforward
...by ibu then if you don't mind operate...can...take a look...
Okay, that's where
...height question you...support the system level api
...to the require just designing...guys.
In general we're supporting privilege api accessible different across the
two different platforms most apps that we worked so far
haven't needed them so we don't have those in the system now except those are called by our own our
own subsystem components if there's something that you need in particular again come by will take
...your thing and search...devices...yeah,
some of those scenarios are going to work and some of them just...to...that we into the limitations of things
like system utilities system utilities a lot of those they just won't work in this world
you really...write those just for a single your targeted they're lower-level...anything else
...consumes so you have differences in
the security miles platforms like being able to share file system files between applications
...api study handle as well as there are different things if you talk about so,
for security itself...do that wrapper we put everything in
the universal windows platform runtime or sandbox so we get
that kind of protection that goes around when you're doing sharing between app
...doing ...and passing something over there...re map the individual
...and passes over so you still have a way of accessing those just like we showed you
this share contract you can do similar kinds of things to do what about your shared files and differences?
Probably more access on android...security.
...in general when their differences and security like
there's some there's some places where android we'll let you do interception of basically
...http stack which is just a fundamentally insecure thing to allow we just don't
allow it were defaulting to let's protect everybody let's
...like...to windows, windows that's right, yeah,
that's right okay so we're not going to compromise security to bring on a apps.
...from usual these people are reading...
Please use...middle...does it work...on windows mobile
...on desktop tablet than this one so it's on mobile today
that we've been focusing on these are apps that are typically written for mobile
so mobile and tablets that are running mobile support all
of those okay and another question do support also...video play
...for android tv android...like
...or it's out of school so some of those are some of those certainly
we don't today there are a new api is like casting and things like
...but we've looked at and there's very little
...yet so we looking we don't see a major need for that so we've been focusing on ones
...apps that we that we see our using a lot more and
...video...works or people video plays is one of the interesting ones because you want to
go intercept the video and move it to our hardware accelerated path I
...and the build we have right now...you know.
Because...I know in eighteen development I know that work...completely done we may have something that we
show now but the way we handle...intercept the request to play and we...onto
...a video...for all of these scenarios we're going to be most optimal back to
deliver the end-user experience...the optimal path requires to switch over to windows and use the
...windows...to do that okay that's what we do all the way throughout here we go and take that intercept
...pass on to our subsystem to go to work
well go ahead a couple of questions one does...support second
Secondary tiles yes saying yes easy I think that's actually...the as
...access to contacts so the address book creating a custom context
...and context we do support there are when you go down the list of local
objects we support most local object access there a few things we still have to add
...context is...on there thank you all go back
...yet two quick questions first one is what android api level
...you making you...things sure so,
looking out...we looked out the wild and...somewhat shocked by the number of
api levels that are that are out there...so.
Everyone we work with right now is targeting fairly old api levels so we support
kit kat so supporting...is actually a lot newer the...almost anybody's targeting today
they're almost no apps that are targeting lollipops natively today requiring lollipops so-so
...kitty-cat should cs for a while and the other question was in
the session yesterday on application lifecycle and windows
...about these new broken sockets that the application get
...wake on socket data reception that will at the
...allowable like methods to these perhaps...I don't know
...so...should we show you an example of...projection eventually we can
...other support for other native windows api projection as well so,...our goal is to
...more of...need a windows api surface why productions?
A...reviews
...duplication is targeted to several.
And, versions...right and the because
...versions provide different bp and the I...several
rocco some site to...my application on time chicks the android
...broker...insight so hollow this problem uses...
...to be handled in your project.
So, you showed it...build time you'll be able to detect that you're building for
...building for...so-if you have to do anything in particular you can go make those updates
but beyond that will also report back to the api level dislike you would in your you access
in your code today so you can take a look at that and see...making runtime...you have to...
I'm not sure our eritrean...on...
my application chicks and...android version in runtime so as which
...will be...award turn cat.
Okay, thank you.
The for the interop library...guys have for
...services ...have has versions of that
...broken out...much smaller components do you support that same.
Broken out structure broken out structures are...like maps if you only want
the maps component of google...services you can at that into their without adding, you know,
another twenty thousand methods which.
Approaches...working on...today we just showed you that's the simple
one one-line mapping but we want to work on that scenarios well okay thanks, yeah, today's everything in a single
gr that when intercepted will go...there.
So, again,...google...services are you supporting the
activity detection portions of that as well do you have andyes, there's a...
Good...regarding the would you services like
...provide background...all dui api so theories
and android so background audio that's one of the background services that we're working on adding we don't have
that yet but that's...mostly...just those differences between the background execution models
and we have that in background audio I believe will be one of the first backers services that we support
...regarding all the other api site you...to do foreground
...there lots of like the media extract...
Audio tracks...mobiles classes that...are those
...already supported in projectors to where you
...to look at individual ones typically if something is popular were a lot more likely to have the support
...already and we'll just add things as people need so I can't answer
for particular one there we have to go to scanner thing take a look
...tons and tons of possible methods there so we can scan it take a look and see
we have support for become by...both and we'll take a look.
I have an app which has native code as well as a...we kind of they switch back and forth
...yet so how does that scenario play out...works just fine we support native code
we support java code we...web use embedded we all those things together so...very common app
...pattern so we had a sport that...you get converted to windows...control the web you
...today is not yet is one of the things that we're looking at would really like to the edge
engine is pretty cool so, we want to get on that but we're not there today again our approach that
...take for each of these scenarios are going to take the most optimal
back that was the best end-user experience without compromising the scenario?
...specific question you might not be able to answer on windows phone economic sample audio
forty-eight kilohertz but...you can...lots of different sample rate and I have an...samples
...twenty-two kilohertz...just wondering...just work on windows phone.
Let's see...audio version.
You know, we have not looked at that scenario but I think but,
you know, but, like he said earlier...look at the cluster map and that's not...is important to ensure we will
...us we...greatest again stop at the...and
...definitely one of the quiz question if you have a native ios often...native
...up and you want to use these...technologies to make a windows phone up which is the best
...to use ... it's they use have different different approaches so you
...if you've got both of those things first clearly if you
have windows code go with windows code...be the best on the platform you
...the broadest places you can do the most stuff it's clearly the best thing to do with
the driving all the upgrades and all that it'll be a huge opportunity if
you got just ios...android code.
You look at it in one
questions you ask yourself do is one of the my lead code base do I lead with one of these or do the development
...this one first importers this one if so that's going to that's going to
...one direction or another the next thing would be
you say okay I'm going to do some work on the project island would side
iranians ios iowa's code there you have to do a little bit more work
in visual studio but in exchange for that you get full access to the platform you to call
intothe whole universal windows platform which is which is a valuable so on the on
the astoria side you don't typically have to do as much work it's usually very little
overhead but you don't have as much integration available...the system so that's a tradeoff that you have?
Okay,I have one question for the native code this point, yeah,
so, if ...force such kind
...pages say use native...to.
Develop and, your applications as a use open geo
...so do...she's kind of replicate
...if we do now soccer games and in particular so
games we support open gl we support open...with high framework rate we go and
...that over using angle nowthe on games a lot of games
more and more are being built on middleware if you're built on something like unity has great
native support for windows already your best path there is going to be just using unity and...
having a windows build target that's very straightforward to do so if you have that
if you have that kind of middleware the makes it easier go on that path
you don't have that kind of middleware than this is something you should check out and a...is that to the
cost for ngos as different kind of hardware api,
for example, ...
Eighty-six the eighty-six.
...maybe...medius.
...a hardware spec so
...requirement on the http uploaded to check.
So,...are you asking about android an x eighty-six or asking about like
neon optimizations or what kinds of things
...when I...is that the when I compile?
And,...with native...
A I can choose the hardware settings and like choose
...for arm or choose to the to
...to be can rather compatible with each rx
...yep so it's will be...case yes so
...upload...if you case to be checked with you are solution
which.
...which kind of west back we expect will today the most important
one to move up is arm is the platform that we have soul mobile devices
...on but we actually want to encourage make it really easy to go submit both
...both of those flavors up there to make them available the
...support, you know, I'm devices so you should start with your...version of the
...going forward we plan to support more hardware platforms ok,
...these are the last three and then ...pattern over to the insiders launch answer anymore
...so approach for android widgets and...there do you have in mind
...maybe convert...to windows...at some point or is this is outside the scope we
have the...there yet we're focusing more inside traditional apps thanks?
Hi, android...different layout folders so you could
target of different screen sizes different densities different accounts of
...just work on windows phone so what we're trying to do is handle things like the
you-can query and resolution...and...layout based on that we handle those queries
by return back the values of course...those windows api so we can drive the same transitions
...you have things like on rotation you go you will tear down your
...and rebuild rebuild for your new orientation...the same kind of we pass
...the same thing when we move around the devices during a demo here but we do that same
stuff so our goal is to make that seamless we've just been which go through and fixing bugs...we had
...okay so...from the toads perspective forget query but what about just layout folders
like happen landscape layout and...such
as I believe that we do handle both of those because those are pulled into runtime
...behind-the-scenes and we handle...runtime checks so I do.
All...stuff that we've done there has worked so far and I believe we...work.
How about the bluetooth stack support...both bluetooth and
...so this is something that we don't have a bunch of low-level support
their bluetooth yet...something that people really want will prioritize it...there I mean this
...earlier first-time we talked about this yesterday so this is fresh?
we're going to be we're going to take feedback what about the scenario where you'd want to upgrade
the app to a native ...and...migrations strategy while you're
going to be able just replace the replace the app in the store with something that's
there now beyond that we're trying to give you were looking into some tools what can we do to can make that easy
because we really want everyone to go build apps that are deeply
differentiate we want to use all the all the skills that people already have making
...into the platform we also...reach the broadest number devices so we want to
make that paths as easy as we possibly can we don't I mean tools and place today you have
to go and do the work of create a new version then we you it is straightforward
...store so this is definitely a long-term strategy not just a
stopgap solution negate happen...
You know, I think I'd still they pretty clearly
our primary strategy you probably heard a lot about universal windows asks
...to days what that is what the question
stem from like if we wanted to write...windowed or windows app.
...want to...sooner...happening or...yeah,
seems like an attractive, yeah,
this is a it's a great way toprosciutto in the water when you want to do the best experience
some ofbroadest...broadest update...urinating.
Tool thanks-very-muchcome...the windows insiders...more questions.